《越狱》  前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
你得了下丘脑错构瘤
You have hypothalamus Hamartoma,
医生认为你需要手术
the doctor feels you need surgery
否则  你会死
Otherwise you could die
你不听命令吗
You are not following direct orders?
我听命令  长官
Oh, I'm following direct orders, sir.
只不过不听你的了
Just not from you anymore.
如果不是你  我就死在这张桌子上了
I would've died on this table if it weren't for you, Doc.
干嘛
What?
该回家了
Time to come home now.
你要帮我找一个新的买家
You're going to help me find a new buyer for Scylla.
他叫怀肯  他不是买家  是个中间人
His name is Vikan, and he's not a buyer, he's a conduit.
我们走吧
Let's go.
巴格维尔留在这里
And Bagwell's staying here.
我警告过你别耍我
I warned you not to screw me over.
别来无恙  格雷琴  他是谁
It's been a long time, Gretchen. Who's he?
"锡拉"在我手上
I'm the guy that's holding Scylla.
这是不完整的  少了一个部件  小子
It's incomplete. There's a piece missing, slick.
你好啊  唐
Hello, Don.
我相信你拿了我的东西
I believe you have something that belongs to me.
过来拿吧
Come and get it.
你应该知道  这不是什么灵丹妙药
Just so it's fresh in your mind, this isn't a magic elixir.
你还是要去医院
You still need a hospital.
你需要真正的仪器
You need real equipment.
或者找一个
Could probably use a doctor
有医疗执照的医生
who's still got a license to practice medicine.
首先  我们要找回"锡拉"
First we get Scylla.
然后  我才去医院
Then I'll go to the hospital.
你弄完了吗
You finished?
差不多了
Just about.
你现在准备说话了
So, I take it you're ready to talk now?
事实上  我准备好和你见面了
Actually, I'm ready to meet.
我有一个更好的主意
I got a better idea.
所有人都出去
Everyone out!
你被包围了
You're surrounded.
把"锡拉"部件交出来  迈克尔
Come out with your piece of Scylla, Michael.
你先交
You first.
出来吧  不然  我就用烟把你们熏出来
Come out, or I'm going to gas you out.
如果你们被熏出来  我有满满的一梭子子弹
If it's the latter, I have a full magazine with 30 rounds.
想赌一把  看是不是有人跑得比你快
Want to bet at least one of them could outrun you?
你凭什么认为  我把部件带在身上
What makes you think I'd even keep the piece on me?
我了解你  迈克尔
Oh, I know you, Michael.
你随身带着那块东西
You're not letting that thing out of your sight.
我还是那句话
I stand by my original offer.
过来拿吧
Come and get it.
好吧
Okay.
趴低点  等烟升到天花板
Stay low. Let the gas rise to the ceiling.
这里空间很大  但是  在我们窒息前
This is a big space, but it won't take many more of those
撑不了多久
before we start to asphyxiate.
林肯在哪
Where's Lincoln?!
还多着呢  迈克尔
Here we go, Michael.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：zwzy_1007(胖胖)
《越狱》第四季 第十四集
Prison.Break.S04E14
好了  我们现在开车去拿"锡拉"
All right, now we take a ride and we pick up Scylla.
不然  我就一枪崩了你
Or I put a bullet in your head.
不可能
It ain't gonna happen.
试试看
Try me.
大家早
Good morning.
现在  大家都被枪指着
Okay, all right, now that we all have guns pointed at us,
我们谈谈吧  好吗
let's talk, okay?
说吧
Fine.
你先告诉我  我到底是在和谁说话  是唐吗
You could start by telling me who I'm talking to, Don?
我在过去17年里
You're talking to a guy who spent 17 years
规规矩矩为政府卖命
in service of his government, all by the book.
你知道  这些值多少钱吗
You know what the sum total of it was?
一文不值  什么都不是
Nothing. Nada.
我们是一类人  迈克尔
But we're very similar, Michael,
而且  从根本来说  我们要的是同一样东西
and fundamentally, we want the same thing.
我有方法拿到手
And I have a way to get it.
什么意思
How's that?
我找了一个"锡拉"买家
I got a buyer for Scylla.
一个和你一样  想搞垮"公司"的人
A guy who wants to destroy the Company as much as you do.
他愿意付一大笔钱
And he's willing to pay a lot of money for it.
多少钱
How much?
你选一个国外帐号  九位数
Nine figures in an offshore account of your choosing.
就是这样
So, there it is.
或者
Or...
你可以继续按你的原则办事
you could stand by your principles.
我不干
I'll pass.
我是骗了你  我承认
Look, I burned you, right?
我道歉  但是  有意义吗
And I'd apologize, but what's the point?
我们的处境都很尴尬
We're all out in the cold now.
但是  我们不可能一直躲着"公司"
But we're not going to be able to hide from the Company
我们根本没有本钱
on a shoestring budget.
谁是买家
Who's the buyer?
他以前在"公司"做事  有过节
He's an ex-Company guy with a bone to pick.
和你爸一样
Just like your father.
迈克尔
Michael?
我要先和他见面
I'd need to meet him first.
可以安排
That can be arranged.
只是想告诉你
And just so you know, this...
这不是私人恩怨  只是笔交易
This wasn't personal. This is just business.
我会和你联络的
We'll be in touch.
我们还是按原计划行事
We stick to the plan, all right?
我们会拿回"锡拉"
We're going to get Scylla.
只要等阿历克斯那头打通关系
We wait for Alex to come through on his end.
好吗
All right?
你好  阿历克斯
Hello, Alex.
你来了
You came.
我一向遵守承诺
I always do,
就算会被扣工钱
to the detriment of my pay grade.
过去几个星期
These last few weeks,
我参与了一起秘密行动
I've been part of an off-the-books operation
是国安局安排的
under the hand of Homeland Security.
费丽舍  和我共事的人
Felicia, the people I'm working with,
我们就差那么一点
we're this close to coming up with
就能得到摧毁"公司"的东西
the one thing that can destroy the Company:
他们的黑皮书  我们能搞到手  里面有姓名  数字
their little black book. We can get it. Names, numbers.
我可不想夹在部门间的斗争里
Look, I don't want to get caught up in some interagency politics.
如果这次国安局的行动
So, if this is Homeland's show...
国安局终止了行动  我们不能再回去了
Homeland buried the operation. We can't come back in.
但是  我们还可以搞垮"公司"
But we could still take the Company down.
所以  我的问题是
So, my question to you is:
在联调局里  你认为可以信任谁
Who do you know in the Bureau that you can trust?
以前是你  阿历克斯
It used to be you, Alex.
过去几个月  我失去了很多东西
I've lost a lot of things these last few months,
不止是你的信任
not the least of which is your trust.
但我不是来乞求你的
But I don't come to you hat in hand.
"锡拉"是存在的
Scylla is real.
如果你不想扯上关系  我可以理解
But if you don't want anything to do with it, it's okay.
没事  我可以离开
It's all right; I could walk away.
有一个人也许能帮你
Yeah, there is someone who might be able to help.
长官  洛杉矶有超过1千万人口
Sir, there are over ten million faces in Los Angeles.
加上安全局和情报局的卫星  我们需要过滤
Even with NSA and CIA satellite links, we're going to be sifting
几百万G的图像数据
through millions of gigabytes of image data.
找到唐·赛尔夫
The chances of finding Don Self,
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯的几率  不是很高
Scofield and Burrows... it's not good.
让我们增加几率
Well, let's improve the odds.
赛尔夫和兄弟俩
Self and the brothers
是偷了"锡拉"  但是
may have stolen Scylla but none of them have
他们没有任何办法出售
the connections to off-load it.
在查找中加上格雷琴的脸
Add Gretchen's face to the search.
她不可能是斯科菲尔德小组的一员
She won't be welcome in Scofield's camp.
把她和赛尔夫的图像联系到一起
So, connect her image with Self's.
如果在洛杉矶任何5尺距离内
We find those two within five feet of each other
找到他们  我们就能找到"锡拉"
anywhere in Los Angeles, and we've found Scylla.
你是格雷琴阿姨的朋友吗
Are you friends with my Auntie Gretchen?
去你的房间玩  妈妈一会就过去
Go play in your room. Mommy will be in soon.
她爸爸在哪
Where's her daddy?
格雷琴从来不提及他
Gretchen doesn't talk about him.
艾米丽还不知道你不是她的
So, Emily doesn't know that you ain't...
格雷琴是她妈妈
That Gretchen's her mama?
不  我宁愿保持这种方式
No, and I'd like to keep it that way.
可爱的孩子
Cute girl.
不要伤害我的孩子
Don't hurt my little girl.
如果你要做什么  冲我来吧
If you have to do something, do it to me.
你以为我是什么人
What do you think I am?
野兽
A monster?
你把我们囚禁在我们家里
You're holding us prisoner in our own home.
我和你们一样  都是囚犯
I'm just as much a prisoner as you.
奶白色  黑体字
Eggshell white. Bold lettering.
双层浮花  我曾经是科尔·普发
Double embossed. I was Cole Pfeiffer.
受人尊敬的商人
Respected businessman.
东北区域最好的推销员
Top salesman in the Northeast Region.
现在  我又变回过去的
Now I'm back being prisoner
囚犯身份
of my own identity.
帝博格·巴格维尔  罪犯
Theodore Bagwell. Convict.
管他呢  江山易改  本性难移  对吧
To hell with it. We are who we are, right?
你是卖什么的
What were you selling?
你管不着
Never you mind.
你只要祈祷你妹妹能脱险
You just pray your sister comes through.
"公司"被搞垮  我们拿到钱
The Company gets destroyed  and we get paid.
这买卖其实不错
It's a great deal.
这个人只会是另一个克兰兹将军
This guy is just another General Krantz waiting to happen.
假设我们把"锡拉"买给他  这个"公司"倒了
Let's say we do sell it to him and the Company burns,
你知道接下来会怎样吗
You know what happens then?
另一个"公司"会在前者之上建立
Another company is built right on top of that one.
我们不卖
We're not selling.
我进去了
I'm in.
苏克雷搞定了
Sucre pulled it off.
好极了
Great.
找出地点
Get an address.
有用吗
Is this going to work?
这就象超声波
It's like an ultrasound.
能透视所有东西
It can see through everything.
你这是增大耐药量
You're building up a tolerance.
那就加大剂量
Then we'll up the dosage.
对  我增加了
Yeah, I have,
但这样的话  大剂量会比肿瘤本身
and at this point, a higher dosage would have
带来更多的副作用
more side effects than the tumor itself.
我会尽量不用它
I'll manage without it.
你坐在这等着
Sit this one out.
让我和苏克雷来处理
Let me and Sucre handle it.
我也去
I'm going.
他怎么就不理解  我要结束这一切
Why can't he understand I need to finish this?
所发生的一切
Everything that happened,
都是"公司"引起的
it all started with the Company.
也许林肯不这么认为
Maybe not for Lincoln.
也许对他来说  这一切
Maybe for him, this all started
是从他弟弟救他越狱开始的
with his little brother breaking him out of prison.
迈克尔  你救了他的命
Michael, you saved his life.
如果你有什么不测
If anything happens to you,
他下辈子都会愧疚
he spends the rest of his life feeling guilty for that.
告诉我
Tell me something,
什么时候一件高尚的事变成了狂热盲从
at what point does a noble deed become fanaticism?
狂热是打败他们的唯一方法
Fanaticism is the only way to beat them.
即使为此丧命吗
Even if it kills you?
打开车尾箱
Hey, pop the trunk.
方特罗伊旅店停车场
Fauntleroy Hotel Parking only.
迈克尔
Micheal?
苏克雷刚发了条信息  他发现格雷琴和赛尔夫了
Sucre just sent a text. He's found Gretchen and Self.
很好  很好
Good, good.
你没事吧
You all right?
目前还好
Yeah, for now.
好的
All right.
-林肯  -什么
-Linc?  -Yeah?
当天审判过后  我去福克斯河监狱看你
After your trial that day I came to see you at Fox River...
怎么了
What about it?
我认为是你干的
I thought you did it.
我认为是你杀了特伦斯·斯特曼
I thought you killed Terrence Steadman.
其他人也这么想吗
Along with everyone else?
但我离开的时候
But by the time I left, I...
我知道你是无辜的
I knew you were innocent.
我一定要把你从里面弄出来
And I had to get you out of that place.
不管这次结果怎样
So, however this plays out,
我决不后悔
I have no regrets.
斯科菲尔德在厕所藏了东西
Scofield's hiding something in the washroom.
看来我们找到了
I think we just found
缺失的"锡拉"部件了  给怀肯打电话
our missing piece of Scylla. Call Vikan.
我要先跟我女儿通话
I want to talk to my daughter first.
只管给怀肯打电话  她们没事
Just call him, okay, they're fine.
我跟怀肯有过交易
I have a history with Vikan.
如果我不告诉他你没问题  他是不会交易的
No money exchanges hands unless I tell him you're legit.
我要跟我女儿通话  马上
I want to talk to my daughter. Now!
喂
Yeah?
让她女儿听电话
Put the daughter on the phone.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
只管让她听电话
Just put her on the phone.
喂
Hello?
艾米丽  宝贝  我是格雷琴阿姨
Emily, baby, it's your Auntie Gretchen.
你在哪
Where are you?
不远的地方  你还好吗
I'm not far. Are you okay?
这里有个坏人
There's this mean man here.
艾米丽  宝贝  还记得
Emily, baby, do you remember the mean man
以前跟你妈妈丽塔一起住的坏人吗
that used to live with your mommy Rita?
那个对你大吼大叫的人
The one that used to yell at you all the time?
罗伊吗
Roy?
就是他
That's the one.
罗伊最后怎么了
And what happened to Roy?
有一天  他去商店
He went to the store one day
就再没回来了
and never came back.
没错
That's right.
我觉得  如果你不喜欢这个坏人
And I think that if you don't like this mean man,
很快  他就会走
then very soon, he's going to leave
永远不会再回来
and he's never coming back.
真的吗
You think so?
宝贝  是真的
Baby, I know so.
行了  够了
All right, that's enough.
艾米丽  宝贝  让那个坏人接电话
Emily, baby, put the mean man back on the phone.
听着  我两小时内给你打电话
Listen to me. I'm going to call you
告诉你准确的交易地址
in two hours with the exact location of the exchange.
如果我没打电话
If you don't hear from me,
就把她们杀了
kill them both.
你有客人吗
You expecting somebody?
没有
No.
自然点
Look lively.
宝贝
Hey, buttercup, why don't you
去房间玩吧
go play with your dollsies or something.
没事的  宝贝  回房间玩吧
It's okay, honey. Go to your playroom.
你们好
Hi, there.
我叫拉尔夫·贝克  我是卖圣经的
My name is Ralph Becker, and I'm selling Bibles
为圣三一教会筹集善款
to raise money for the Church of the Holy Trinity.
不知你们能否花5分钟
And I wonder if I could spend five minutes
我们谈谈福音
of your time and talk about the Gospel with you.
拉尔夫  我们现在有点  不太方便
We're a bit, uh, indisposed at the moment, Ralph.
明天再来吧
Can you come back tomorrow?
今天是筹款的最后一天
Well, actually, today is the last day of the fund-raiser.
我说我们很忙
I said we're busy.
但总能为上帝抽出点时间吧
We're never too busy for God.
在他的王国里
And what's a few minutes
在下午抽出点时间  怎么样
of your afternoon for a place in His kingdom?
朋友  你这圣经推销员可有点强求
You're a bit pushy for a Bible salesman, ain't you, friend?
我有使命在身
I'm on a mission.
你有使命在身  对吧
You're on a mission, right?
-你在做什么  -关门
-What are you doing?!  -Close the door!
-他是"公司"的人  -什么"公司"
-This guy is Company!  -What company?!
拿绳子把他捆起来
Get me some rope to tie him up with.
他只是个圣经推销员
This guy is a Bible salesman.
去拿绳子  现在就去
Get me the rope, now!
阿历克斯  很会选见面地点嘛
Good choice for a meeting spot, Alex.
人多  两个出口
Crowded place. Two exits.
墙角的座位  整个房间的动静尽收眼底
Corner table with a full view of the room.
看来你习惯逃亡的生活了
Looks like you're getting acclimated to life on the run.
听说你升职了
I hear you got promoted.
有自己的办公室  惠勒
Your own field office, Wheeler.
真是让人印象深刻
That's impressive.
如果你不是丢了联调局的脸
When you're neither a disgrace to the Bureau
或者犯毒瘾  你也能摊上这样的好事
nor a drug addict, good things can happen.
他都戒掉了  马克
He's clean, Mark.
谢谢提醒   费丽舍
Thank you, Felicia.
我知道你为人  马克
Look, I know you, Mark.
你是一名好特工  有雄心壮志
You're a good agent, ambitious.
让我助你一臂之力
So, let me appeal to the side of you
让你的名字上头条
that likes to see your name in print.
想进副局长候选人名单吧
Want to be on a short list for Deputy Director? Huh?
没错  朗格把我加进去了
Right. Lang filled me in.
你原本已十拿九稳
You've got solid gold intel.
我不知道我是否比一个被炒的联调员
I don't know if I'm more skeptical of a burned out ex-Fed
或一个被称为"公司"的神秘组织让人怀疑
or the mythical cabal known as the Company.
你大老远来就为了个秘密
You came all the way here for a myth?
你想怎样  阿历克斯
What do you want, Alex?
费丽舍跟我说你是司法部长的耳目
Felicia tells me you have the attorney general's ear.
没错
That's right.
联调局在密谋交易
The Bureau is compromised.
国安局也在密谋交易
Homeland Security is compromised.
我要一个我能信任的人  我能相信你吗
I need someone I can trust. Can I trust you?
你能给我打垮"公司"的可靠情报
You get me credible intelligence against the Company...
我就亲自
I'll walk you into the
去找司法部长
attorney general's office myself.
我们会拿到的
We'll get it.
阿历克斯  说吧
Alex, talk to me.
我在政府里找到能相信的人了
I think I found someone in government we can trust.
你们还要多久才能拿到"锡拉"
How close are you to getting Scylla?
-快了  -迈克尔
Very. Michael...
我们这有委托人  你们一定得搞定才行
We're in escrow here. You've got to come through with the house.
别担心
Don't worry.
我们就快拿到"锡拉"了
We're getting Scylla.
好吧
All right.
看我找到什么了
Look what I found.
问题是  没法用来射他们
Problem is, there's no way to shoot them.
可以
Yeah, we do.
但需要你去买点发胶和打火机
But i need you to buy some hairspray and a lighter.
这是什么
What's this?
我的辞呈
My resignation.
丽莎  我已经够保护你
Lisa, I tried to shield you from everything
不让你做无法胜任的事
I didn't think you could handle.
你唯一保护我的事
The only thing you shielded me from
是不让我知道你真正的为人
was knowing who you really are.
我现在知道了
Now I know.
我原本想要个儿子
I wanted a son.
长官
Sir...
一小时前拍到的
Taken less than an hour ago.
你是对的  格雷琴和赛尔夫在一起
You were right-- Gretchen's with Self.
你们的任务是安全地拿回"锡拉"
Your mission is the safe retrieval of Scylla.
任务的限制呢
one of the Rules of engagement?
格杀勿论
there are none shoot on side
方特罗伊酒店  在市中心
Fauntleroy Hotel, downtown.
谁派你来的
Who sent you?!
圣三一教会
The Church of The Holy Trinity.
说谎
Liar!
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?!
你在打一个
You're beating up
圣经推销员
a Bible salesman!
我不是斯科菲尔德
I ain't Scofield.
我也不是布伦斯
I ain't Burrows.
我不是我的命运  干嘛要来找我
This ain't my lot! Leave me alone!
我不是什么
I'm not a part of this
"公司"的人
Company!
我什么都不知道  我发誓
I don't know anything, I swear.
看看他  求求你  看他
Look at him! Please, please, just look at him!
难道他看起来像
Does he look like some kind
什么卧底吗
of a undercover agent to you?!
他们很会掩人耳目
They blend in!
这就是为什么他们能抓到你
That's how they get you!
看这个  他的钱包  行吧
Look at this.Okay, his wallet, okay?
他有加州的驾驶执照
He's got a California driver's license.
拉尔夫·贝克
"Ralph Becker," okay?
他还有借书卡和祈祷卡
He's got a library card and a prayer card.
这够说服力了吧
That is pretty convincing.
看看
Look at this.
自由  荣誉  国家
"Freedom, Honor, Country.
东南军校  98届
Southeastern Military Academy, Class of '98."
有多少圣经推销员
How many Bible salesman do you know graduate
是从军校毕业的
from a military academy?!
不是的  我没去东南军校  这是我弟弟的戒指
No! I didn't go to Southeastern! It's my kid brother's ring!
他去年在巴格达死了
He died in Baghdad last year!
死于汽车爆炸事件
It was a car bomb!
我发誓
I swear!
听我说
Listen to me.
这么说是真的
That made sense.
行了吧
Okay...
这讲得通
that made sense.
求你了
Please!
除非我接到电话
We're not going nowhere!
我们哪儿都不许去
Not till I get a phone call!
一小时25美元
It's $25 for the hour.
我们不是来开房的
We don't need a room.
我在找我姐姐
I, uh, I'm looking for my sister.
她的名字是格雷琴·摩根
Her name's Gretchen Morgan.
你能告诉我她住哪间房吗
Can you tell me what room she's in?
你想查什么  就打411
You want information, call 411.
现在呢
How about now?
没有叫格雷琴·摩根的人
No Gretchen Morgan.
没有退款
No refund.
她差不多五尺七
She's about five-seven.
黑头发和蓝眼睛
She's got black hair and blue eyes,
我想她在这么"漂亮"的旅店
and I imagine she'd stand out
里一定很抢眼
in a fine establishment like this one.
308房
Room 308.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不准在楼道尿尿
No urinating in the stairwell.
这是明文规定
That's the golden rule.
喂
Yeah?
他们在三楼
Yeah, they're on the third floor,
从旅店正面看
front of the hotel,
就在中间的左边
just to the left of center.
收到  谢谢
Got it, thanks.
在三楼  阳台左边
Third floor up, just left of the balcony.
就装在那边楼顶上吧
Why don't you set up on that rooftop over there?
"锡拉"已经快搞定了
Scylla's almost complete.
你那头准备好了吗
Is everything ready on your end?
让我跟格雷琴谈
Let me talk to Gretchen.
不  你跟我谈
No, you're talking to me.
买家已经到了
The buyer has touched down.
他们可没耐性等你
This isn't the kind of person you keep waiting.
我也一样
Likewise.
让他们把钱准备好
Just make sure he has the money ready.
听着  臭小子
Listen to me, you mook.
你现在已在深水区
You're in the deep end of the pool now.
至少装着你会游泳
At least act like you can swim.
下次打电话时  我要和格雷琴说话
And the next time I call, I want to talk to Gretchen.
不  你听我说
No, no, no, you listen to me, okay?
下次你打过来
The next time you call, it better be
最好告诉我钱准备好了  懂了吗
to tell me that the money's ready, you understand?
喂
Hello.
我想让你知道
I thought you should know
有一个男的和一个女的来找你了
a man and a woman came in looking for you.
-斯科菲尔德找到我们了  -怎么可能
Scofield found us. How?
我不管  做好准备
Who cares? Just get ready.
多久前的事
How long ago?
几分钟
A couple of minutes.
我可不想我的地方有麻烦
I don't want no trouble in my place!
我去检查一下走廊
I'm gonna recon the hallway.
有情况的话  带上"锡拉"离开
Anything goes down, get Scylla, get out.
我会去找你
I will find you.
好的
Okay.
迈克尔  就像我说的  这只是笔交易
Michael, like I said before, this is just business.
我的耳朵
My ear!
不许动
Don't move!
上车
Get in!
帮我把他抬到车厢里
Help me get him in the back of the van!
迈克尔
Michael!
那是什么
What is that?
是仓库
It's the warehouse.
那个芯片
The chip.
你确定在这儿
You sure it's here?
是  我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
从图上看  只可能在一个地方
From the schematic, it can only be in one place.
别犯傻  好吧  格雷琴
Look, don't be stupid, okay, Gretchen?
你能要回你的女儿和钱
You're gonna get your daughter back and your money.
我在车上等你
I'll see you in the car.
他被带来时就这样
He was brought in like this.
谁在那儿
Who's there?
我给他注射十毫升氯硝安定
I'm giving him 10cc's of clonazepam
把他带到楼下  很快就有结果
and taking him downstairs. We'll know more soon.
尽量放松
Try and relax.
不用担心  我们会把迈克尔救回来的
Don't worry, we're gonna get Michael back.
怎么救  赛尔夫把部件拿走了
How? Self took the piece.
我们没有筹码做交换
We got nothing to trade for Michael.
他病了  林肯
He's sick, Lincoln.
如果他们还没杀他
If they haven't killed him already...
我们就能把他救回来  我保证
We'll get him back, I promise.
喂
Hello.
等一下
Hold on.
是阿历克斯
It's Alex.
喂
Yeah.
你们拿到了吗
Did you get it yet?
没有  赛尔夫拿走了
No, Self's got it.
全部
All of it.
什么
What?
别说"锡拉"了
Just forget about Scylla.
"公司"抓走了迈克尔
The Company's taken Michael.
你在政府里的朋友  能帮忙救他吗
Your friend in government.can he do anything for him?
不  他帮不上忙
No, I don't think so.
你没理由再回来了  阿历克斯
There's no reason for you to come back, Alex.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我也很抱歉
Yeah, me, too.
早就知道
Should have known.
怀肯在这和我们见面吗
Vikan's meeting us here?
"公司"的雷达监测不到这里
We'll be off the Company's radar here.
喂
Yeah.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
不管什么麻烦  都可以等
Well, whatever it is, it can wait.
我们在最后关头了
We're in the home stretch here.
带上她妹妹和女儿
Grab the sister and the girl.
我会再打给你
I'm going to call you back
告诉你准确的交易地点
with the exact location of the exchange.
我非常乐意  但是
I'd love to, but a, uh...
有第三方人插手这事
third party has been introduced into the mix.
谁
Who?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
他可能是"公司"的人
He might be a Company operative.
那就杀了他
So kill him.
也可能只是个卖圣经的
He could also be a Bible salesman.
那他进天堂
Then he should have no problem
就没问题了  杀了他
getting past St. Peter. Kill him.
带你女儿
Go back in the playroom
-回房间玩  -你要做什么
with your daughter. What are you going to do?
快去
Go now!
求你  求你  别杀我
Please... please, please don't kill me.
求你别杀我
Please don't kill me.
求你  我不会告诉任何人
Please... Look, I won't tell anyone!
我不会说的  我保证
I won't tell anyone, I promise!
求你别杀我
Please don't kill me!
我发誓  我不会说的
I swear I won't tell anyone.
别这么做
Don't do this.
我说了回房间去
I told you to go back yonder, okay?
你不会想看到这些
You don't want to see this!
科尔·普发不会这么做
Cole Pfeiffer won't do this.
科尔·普发已不复存在了
Cole Pfeiffer ain't here no more.
只有帝博格
Just ol' T-Bag.
我们的天父
Our Father who art in Heaven
愿你的名受显扬
hallowed be thy name...
你想获得自由吗
You want to be free?
现在就开始吧
Start now.
就是现在
Right this minute.
如果你扳动了扳机
If you pull that trigger...
科尔·普发就永远消失了
Cole Pfeiffer is gone forever.
不要这样
Don't do this.
拉尔夫  我的父亲以前也是个教徒
You know, my daddy was a religious man, too, Ralph,
就像你一样
just like you.
我们以前一起
We used to... pray together
晚上在我房间祈祷
in my room at night.
我总是跪在地上哭泣
I used to go down to the floor crying
就像你现在这样
just like you now.
有时  我再也受不了
Sometimes when I just couldn't take it no more,
我爸爸就会背一段
my daddy would recite a particular piece
他喜欢的经文给我听
of Scripture that he was fond of...
一宿
"Weeping
虽有哭泣
may endure through the night..."
早晨便必欢呼
"But joy cometh in the morning."
圣经诗篇的第30首之5
Psalms 30:5.
丽塔
Rita...
什么事
Yeah?
你有车吗
Have you got a car?
我的车  在车库里
My car's in the... it's in the garage.
你现在就上车
You get in that car right now
开得远远的  越远越好
and you drive far, far away from right here,
现在就走  好吗
right now, okay?
这个
Here.
拿着
Take this.
丽塔
Rita...
谢谢你
Thank you.
你要对我做什么
What are you going to do to me?
我让你走
I want you to go.
让你获得自由
I want you to be free.
像我一样自由
Be as free as me.
谢谢
Thank you.
十分感谢
Thank you so much.
我抓到一个
Yeah, I got one.
不是格雷琴  是巴格维尔
Not Gretchen. It's Bagwell.
我这就把他带走
I'm bringing him in.
是恶性肿瘤
The growth is malignant.
挤压到他的颞叶
It's pushing up against his temporal lobe
如果不切除  他会死
and it will kill him if it's not removed.
你之前
Have you seen
见过这种病例吗
anything like this before?
这么严重的
This advanced?
一例
Once.
长官
Sir...
你绝对想不到  谁在外面
You'll never guess who just came through the door.
我要见我弟弟
I want to see my brother.
谢谢  先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
布伦斯先生不会出问题  对吧
Mr. Burrows, won't be a problem... will you?
这事因我而起  也应由我结束
This started with me. It ends with me.
放迈克尔走
Let Michael go.
我想你做了一个正确的决定
I think you made the right decision.
我们下楼去看你弟弟吧
Let's go downstairs and see your brother.
格雷琴
Gretchen.
唐  这次最好是真货
Don... this better be the real thing this time.
全在这了
It's all here.
恕我冒犯
Well, no offense,
但我还是要亲自检验一下
but I'll check it myself.
买家在路上了吗
So the buyer's on the way?
他马上就到
He will be here shortly.
他把钱带来了吗
And he's bringing the money?
是的  唐  他带了钱
Yes, Don, he is bringing the money.
校验完整
Memory Integrity Verified
"锡拉"是完整的
Scylla is complete.
格雷琴  干的不错
Gretchen, you did it.
我倒想看看
What I wouldn't give to see
将军的表情
the look on the General's face.
你这是干什么
What the hell are you doing?!
我们要留活口卖掉这东西啊
We need him alive to sell this thing!
你听见他说的了
You heard what he said.
买家已经在路上了
Buyer's already on the way.
你以为我会给这小子
You think I'm going to give this clown 30%
3成的介绍费吗
for just making introductions?
怎么会错过玻璃门那所房
come on, how could you miss the glass door
好的  我们这就出来
Okay, we'll be right out.
如何
Well?
司法部长愿意听你讲述
The attorney general is willing to hear you out.
从我坐的角度来看
You know, from where I'm sitting, it looked like...
你去往杜勒斯的航班45分钟后起飞
Your flight to Dulles leaves in 45 minutes.
我能信任这个人吗
Can I trust this guy?
我们得走了
We better go.
走吧  阿历克斯  去机场的路很近
Come on, Alex, short trip to the airport.
司法部长在等着呢
Attorney general's waiting.
根本就没有
There is no meeting
和司法部长的会面  是吧
with the attorney general, is there?
谢谢你  费丽舍
Thank you, Felicia.
谢谢你所做的一切
For everything you've done.
一切
Everything.
你对我弟弟做了什么
What did you do to my brother?
迈克尔需要做手术
Michael needs an operation to remove a tumor
把肿瘤从颞叶切除  而且现在就得做
from his temporal lobe, and he needs it now.
"公司"可以提供
The Company can provide
一次手术作为交换
such an operation at a cost.
你要我们做什么
What do you want from us?
不是你们  林肯
Not "us," Link...
是你
you.
这次手术的代价
The price of the operation
就是安全返还"锡拉"
is the safe return of Scylla.
把你们偷的东西还给我
You bring back to me what you stole,
我可以保证迈克尔得到全球最好的
and I will make sure Michael gets the finest medical care
医疗救治
in the world.
公司有超越社会上
The Company has science and technology
几年水平的科学技术
that's years ahead of anything available to the public.
并且都在这里
And it's all right here.
在这个机构
in this facility.
我可以想象
Now I would imagine
为我工作  对你来说难以接受
that working for me would be difficult for you to accept.
这是什么
What's this?
额外奖励
Added incentive.
《墓碑II》